<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Toxipedia</title>
    <link>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Toxipedia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 20:42:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>About This website</title>
        <link>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 22:46:05 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/about/</guid>
        <description>Toxipedia https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/about/ -&lt;p&gt;During the progression of renal failure, a host of compound is retained in the body of uremic
patients; those compounds are excreted by the healthy kidneys under normal conditions. About
100 retention solutes have been recognized at present [1]. Not all of these compounds are
necessarily toxic. They can only be defined as uremic toxins if they have been proven to exert
biochemical/biological action.
[1] Vanholder RC. Retention pattern of uremic solutes: An analysis of the current knowledge (abstract). J Am Soc Nephrol.
2001; 10(12):87A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small water soluble compounds (MW: &amp;lt;500 Da), such as urea (MW: 60 Da). These are
relatively easy to remove by standard dialysis membranes (small pore size – low flux).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small protein-bound solutes (MW also mostly &amp;lt;500Da), such as p-cresol (MW: 108 Da).
Dialytic removal of these solutes is hampered by their protein binding, irrespective of the
membrane type. This results in a behavior comparable to that of the larger molecules. It is of note
that also some larger molecules, such as leptin, are protein bound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The so-called middle molecules (MW: &amp;gt;500Da such as b2-microglobulin (MW: 11,818 Da).
Originally, the upper molecular weight range proposed for the middle molecules was  12,000 Da. In
the meantime, larger molecules with a biological impact have been recognized, e.g., leptin (16,000
Da).
Hemodial Int. 2003; 7(2):156–161.
Inadequate removal of a large number of potentiall toxic organic metabolites from the vascular bed
into the urine in the course of acute kidney injury (AKI) and chronic kidney disease (CKD) is
associated with various clinical symptoms which are often difficult to interpret.
Uremic retention solutes are referred to as uremic toxins when they interact with normal biological
functions. It is of considerable importance to identify which of the uremic retention solutes are
actually uremic toxins and what pathomechanisms are involved in their damaging effect on the
kidneys and other organs.
The term uremic syndrome refers to the clinical picture produced by accumulation in the body of
noxious substances which in health are eliminated into the urine. Although the clinical symptoms of
uremic syndrome have been known for decades, our knowledge of the origin, chemical structure
and composition of the retained endogenous substances responsible for these symptoms is far
from complete
CLASSIFICATION
Based in water solubility, protein binding capacity, molecular weight, pattern of removal by dialysis,
biological properties and potential to produce clinical symptoms.
The most common classification of uremic compounds into 3 groups proposed by EUTox is by
molecular weight, protein-binding capacity and removal pattern by dialysis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low-Molecular-Weight Water-Soluble Uremic Toxins
This group consists of small molecules (molecular weight &amp;lt;500 Da) that are soluble in water and
easily removed by any dialysis strategy. Low-molecular-weight organic compounds may occur in
free water-soluble form or bound to plasma proteins, which alters the function of both the toxin
and the transporter protein. Of the 90 molecules evaluated by EUTox, 68 were found to be
members of this group, the most common compounds being ADMA (asymmetric dimethylarginine),
creatine, creatinine, hyaluronic acid, guanidine, guanidinoacetate, guanidinosuccinate, oxalate,
SDMA (symmetric dimethylarginine), urea and uric acid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein-Bound Solutes
Twenty-five uremic retention solutes, i.e. 27.8% of all uremic compounds evaluated by EUTox, are
included in the protein-bound solutes group. Although the molecular weight of most members of
this group is less than 500 Da, because of their protein-binding capacity they are recognized as
‘difficult to remove’ by dialysis. The main protein-bound solutes include advanced glycation end
products (AGEs), carboxy methyl propyl furanpropionic acid, cytokines, interleukins, tumor necrosis
factor-α (TNF-α), dimethylguanidines, hippuric acid, homocysteine, indole-3-acetic acid, indoxyl
glucuronide, indoxyl sulfate (IS), kynurenic acid, kynurenine, leptin, phenolic compounds, p -cresyl
sulfate ( p -CS), p -cresyl glucuronide, phenol sulfate, phenol glucuronide, phenylacetic acid,
quinolinic acid and retinol-binding protein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middle-Molecular-Weight Molecules
The molecular mass of middle-molecular-weight molecule is above 500 Da. So far more than 50
such compounds have been found to have a cause-and-effect relationship with the origin and
development of many pathophysiological processes. Members of this group include
adiponectin, cystatin C, leptin, motilin, α1-acid glycoprotein, α1-microglobulin, endothelin, ghrelin,
osteocalcin atrial natriuretic peptide, prolactin, retinol-binding protein, β2-microglobulin,
cholecystokinin and vasoactive intestinal peptide.
The EUTox classification does not describe the toxicity of the compounds listed and so far there has
been no effective method of such characterization. It has been suggested that further more precise
classification of the compounds should take into consideration any similarities between their
chemical structures, common biological or organ function, and the anatomical site of their origin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
- https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/about/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>5-hydroxyindole glucuronide</title>
        <link>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/5-hydroxyindole/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 14:56:11 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/5-hydroxyindole/</guid>
        <description>Toxipedia https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/5-hydroxyindole/ -&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternative-names&#34;&gt;Alternative Names&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5-hydroxyindole-3-glucuronide&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;molecular-information&#34;&gt;Molecular Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight: 308.24 g/mol [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/5-Hydroxyindole-3-glucuronide&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
Formula: C13H12NO8 [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/5-Hydroxyindole-3-glucuronide&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
Classification: Water-soluble uremic toxin [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6168896/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-information&#34;&gt;General Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clinical-implications&#34;&gt;Clinical Implications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;5-hydroxyindole glucuronide is a uremic toxin which is known to have an association with the following diseases:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chronic kidney disease [&lt;a href=&#34;Link&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification&#34;&gt;Classification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polar
Water-soluble uremic toxin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PubChem. 5-Hydroxyindole-3-glucuronide. Available from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/5-Hydroxyindole-3-glucuronide&#34;&gt;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/5-Hydroxyindole-3-glucuronide&lt;/a&gt; (accessed Nov 1, 2022).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Masakane I, Sakurai K. Current approaches to middle molecule removal: room for innovation. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2018 Oct 1;33(suppl_3):iii12-iii21. doi: 10.1093/ndt/gfy224. Erratum in: Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2018 Dec 7;:null. PMID: 30281129; PMCID: PMC6168896.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poesen R, Viaene L, Verbeke K, Augustijns P, Bammens B, Claes K, Kuypers D, Evenepoel P. Cardiovascular disease relates to intestinal uptake of p-cresol in patients with chronic kidney disease. BMC Nephrol. 2014 Feb 5;15:53. doi: 10.1186/1471-2369-15-53. PMID: 24499455; PMCID: PMC3920574.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
- https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/5-hydroxyindole/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Hydroquinone Sulfate</title>
        <link>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/hydroquinone_sulfate/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 15:11:18 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/hydroquinone_sulfate/</guid>
        <description>Toxipedia https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/hydroquinone_sulfate/ -&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternative-names&#34;&gt;Alternative Names&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benzene-1,4-diol Sulfate&lt;br&gt;
1,4-Dihydroxybenzene sulfate&lt;br&gt;
p-Hydroquinone sulfate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;molecular-information&#34;&gt;Molecular Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight: 202.20 [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/Hydroquinone_sulfate&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
Formula: C6H6O4S [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/Hydroquinone_sulfate&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
Classification: water-soluble phenolic compound and solubilizer [&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydroquinone_sulfate&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;origins&#34;&gt;Origins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hydroquinone sulfate is not naturally formed in the body, but is derived from topical or oral administration of hydroquinone products. It can be found in the blood and urine after application or consumption of hydroquinone, and its levels can be used to monitor the usage of hydroquinone in the body. However, it is important to note that the presence of hydroquinone sulfate in the body does not necessarily indicate its safety, as long-term exposure to high levels of hydroquinone has been linked to potential toxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-information&#34;&gt;General information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hydroquinone sulfate is a sulfate ester of hydroquinone, a phenolic compound. It is used as a solubilizer in various cosmetic and personal care products [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cosmeticsinfo.org/ingredient/p-hydroquinone&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clinical-implications&#34;&gt;Clinical Implications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skin irritation and redness&lt;br&gt;
Pigmentary changes in skin&lt;br&gt;
Phototoxicity&lt;br&gt;
Formation of free radicals in the body&lt;br&gt;
Genetic mutations&lt;br&gt;
In some cases, it has been linked to cancer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification&#34;&gt;Classification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polar&lt;br&gt;
Water soluble&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APA National Center for Biotechnology Information (2022). PubChem Compound Summary for CID 79441, Hydroquinone Sulfate. Retrieved October 17, 2022 from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/Hydroquinone_sulfate&#34;&gt;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/Hydroquinone_sulfate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosmetics Information (2022). Hydroquinone Sulfate. Retrieved October 17, 2022 from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cosmeticsinfo.org/ingredient/p-hydroquinone&#34;&gt;https://www.cosmeticsinfo.org/ingredient/p-hydroquinone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikipedia (2022). Hydroquinone Sulfate. Retrieved October 17, 2022 from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydroquinone_sulfate&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydroquinone_sulfate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;.&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/hydroquinone_sulfate/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>1,3,7-trimethylurate</title>
        <link>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/trimethylurate/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 01:14:21 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/trimethylurate/</guid>
        <description>Toxipedia https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/trimethylurate/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;alternative-names&#34;&gt;Alternative Names&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trimethyl uric acid&lt;br&gt;
8-oxy-caffeine&lt;br&gt;
caffeol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;molecular-information&#34;&gt;Molecular Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight: 210.19 [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/1_3_7-Trimethyluric-acid&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
Formula: C8H10N4O3 [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/1_3_7-Trimethyluric-acid&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
Classification: water-soluble uremic toxin [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6168896/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-information&#34;&gt;General information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trimethyluric acid is a methyl derivative of uric acid, found occasionally in human urine [&lt;a href=&#34;https://hmdb.ca/metabolites/HMDB0002123&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]. It is a metabolite of caffeine [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/1_3_7-Trimethyluric-acid&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1,3,7-trimethylurate (TMU) is a uremic toxin that is produced by the metabolism of caffeine and theophylline in the liver. It is typically excreted in the urine, but in patients with kidney dysfunction or failure, TMU can accumulate in the bloodstream and cause toxic effects on various organ systems. High levels of TMU have been associated with cardiovascular disease, neurodegenerative disorders, and bone disease. In addition, TMU has been shown to inhibit the activity of certain enzymes in the liver, which can lead to the accumulation of other uremic toxins. Therefore, TMU is an important biomarker for the assessment of kidney function and for the evaluation of the risk of various chronic diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clinical-implications&#34;&gt;Clinical Implications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trimethyluric acid is a uremic toxin which is known to have an association with the following diseases:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asthma&lt;br&gt;
Colorectal cancer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification&#34;&gt;Classification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polar&lt;br&gt;
Water soluble uremic toxin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APA National Center for Biotechnology Information (2022). PubChem Compound Summary for CID 79437, 1,3,7-Trimethyluric acid. Retrieved October 17, 2022 from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/1_3_7-Trimethyluric-acid&#34;&gt;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/1_3_7-Trimethyluric-acid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wishart DS, Tzur D, Knox C, et al., HMDB: the Human Metabolome Database. Nucleic Acids Res. 2007 Jan;35(Database issue):D521-6. 17202168&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Masakane I, Sakurai K. Current approaches to middle molecule removal: room for innovation. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2018 Oct 1;33(suppl_3):iii12-iii21. doi: 10.1093/ndt/gfy224. Erratum in: Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2018 Dec 7;:null. PMID: 30281129; PMCID: PMC6168896.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
- https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/trimethylurate/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>L-Homocitrulline</title>
        <link>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/homocitrulline/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 01:14:21 -0700</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/homocitrulline/</guid>
        <description>Toxipedia https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/homocitrulline/ -&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternative-names&#34;&gt;Alternative Names&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L-Citrulline&lt;br&gt;
2-Amino-5-(carbamoylamino)pentanoic acid&lt;br&gt;
N (6)-carbamoyl-L-lysine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;classification&#34;&gt;Classification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polar&lt;br&gt;
Amino acid&lt;br&gt;
Protein-bound&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;molecular-information&#34;&gt;Molecular Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight: 131.17 [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/L-Homocitrulline&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
Formula: C6H13N3O3 [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/L-Homocitrulline&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;br&gt;
Classification: amino acid [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6168896/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L-homocitrulline is a L-lysine derivative that is L-lysine having a carbamoyl group at
the N(6)-position. It is found in individuals with urea cycle disorders.
Homocitrulline is a one of the products of protein carbamylation is which is formed
by binding isocyanic acid to the ε-NH2 group of the side chain of lysine residues [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27302313/&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-information&#34;&gt;General information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L-Homocitrulline is a non-proteinogenic amino acid and an intermediate in the urea cycle [&lt;a href=&#34;https://hmdb.ca/metabolites/HMDB0002123&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;]. It is produced as a result of protein breakdown in the body by the enzyme argininosuccinate. It is typically cleared by the kidneys, but in patients with kidney dysfunction or failure, L-Homocitrulline can accumulate in the bloodstream and cause toxic effects on various organ systems. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/L-Homocitrulline&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clinical-implications&#34;&gt;Clinical Implications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;L-Homocitrulline has been associated with the following diseases:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erectile dysfunction&lt;br&gt;
Cardiovascular disease&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homocitrulline is an important biomarker in patients with uremia and its increase in
concentration allows distinguishing acute from chronic renal failure and is a risk
factor of mortality.
High levels of L-Homocitrulline have been associated with cardiovascular disease
and neurodegenerative disorders such as Alzheimer’s disease and Rheumatoid
arthritis (RA).
In addition, L-Homocitrulline can react with other uremic toxins to form advanced
glycation end-products (AGEs), which can lead to inflammation and tissue damage.
Therefore, L-Homocitrulline is an important biomarker for the assessment of kidney
function and for the evaluation of the risk of various chronic diseases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;APA National Center for Biotechnology Information (2022). PubChem Compound Summary for CID 79437, L-Homocitrulline. Retrieved October 17, 2022 from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/L-Homocitrulline&#34;&gt;https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/L-Homocitrulline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wishart DS, Tzur D, Knox C, et al., HMDB: the Human Metabolome Database. Nucleic Acids Res. 2007 Jan;35(Database issue):D521-6. 17202168&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Masakane I, Sakurai K. Current approaches to middle molecule removal: room for innovation. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2018 Oct 1;33(suppl_3):iii12-iii21. doi: 10.1093/ndt/gfy224. Erratum in: Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2018 Dec 7;:null. PMID: 3028112&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jaisson, S., Kazes, I., Desmons, A., Fadel, F., Oudart, J.-B., Santos-Weiss, I. C. R., Millart, H., Touré, F., Rieu, P., &amp;amp; Gillery, P. (2016). Homocitrulline as marker of protein carbamylation in hemodialyzed patients. Clinica Chimica Acta, 460, 5–10. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cca.2016.06.009&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cca.2016.06.009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desmons, A., Jaisson, S., Pietrement, C., Rieu, P., Wynckel, A., &amp;amp; Gillery, P. (2016). Homocitrulline: A new marker for differentiating acute from chronic renal failure. Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (CCLM), 54(1). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2015-0398&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1515/cclm-2015-0398&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
- https://linux.ucla.edu/noble/homocitrulline/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 